<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Leo Lopes</title>
    <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Leo Lopes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQL and Power BI - Treating and visualizing data using these tools</title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/sql_dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/sql_dashboard/</guid>
      <description>We have five tables in the &amp;lsquo;xlxs&amp;rsquo; format. The tables are from two Hotel chains in the years 2018,2019 and 2020. The goal is:
Create a Database with these tables in Microsoft Visual studio (MVS) Create a SQL query in order to join the tables that we need Create a dashboard showing some informations from our database So, the first step is to create the Database, so we take the following steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science: Bank Fraud - predicting using machine learning</title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-fraud/</guid>
      <description>In here we have simulated a situation where a bank need to detect fraud using machine learning, we create 3 ML algorithms (Logistic regression, decision tree and random forest) to improve our results and detect in the mostrly efficient manner we could. In our final model we have the numbers:
Accuracy: 0.9994
Precision: 0.9989
Recall: 0.9999
F1: 0.9994,
that points to a good model in the fraud detection.
The confusion graph we obtained using the random forest, see more below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science: Songs Recommendations based on spotify dataset</title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter01/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this program is to build a song reccomendation program. The program in first place analyze some songs features and how it evolves in time. In a next program we can go deep in this analyzes and see how songs envolves in the history music. The second part of the program has a goal of build a song recommendation. To this goal we used the K-Means algorithm and used the PCA method to decrease the number of variables, the K-Means algorithm needs this reducion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science: Titanic spaceship - Kaggle competition </title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this challenge is find out who is going to be transported or not transported to a new dimension using the train data. Link to the challenge in Kaggle.
I&amp;rsquo;m trying to solve this kagle competition using ML algorithms and some data techinics. This notes are divided in three parts:
Data analysis and visualization Try to predict who&amp;rsquo;s survive in the spaceship accident Conclusions A prediction using ML in order to find out who is going to be transported to another dimension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science: Twitter Sentiment Analysis </title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this program is to build a wordcloud about some subject of interest. In this particular case I created about Covid, but the reader can easily change the subject.
What are twitter users thinking about Covid ? Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science: House pricing in Belo Horizonte</title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this notes is to have some information on the house prices in Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil. The plan is:
Clean and visualize the Data in order to obtain some initial information If possible, apply ML algorithms in the data in order to predict the prices Obtain some conclusions in what makes the prices higher. Latitude x Longitude with a mapcolor representing the house price in Belo Horizonte, see more below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics: The Schrodinger equation</title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science: Census</title>
      <link>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leo-lopes.github.io/leo_lopes_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this simulation is find out the income of a person with the data given in the census.csv file. The plan follows:
Clean and visualize the data Apply some ML techniques in the data Conclusions Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
